So we have talked about policy iteration.
我们讨论了策略迭代
We have also learned about truncated policy iteration.
并且讨论了截断策略迭代
In this case, the policy evaluation step is
即只对整个状态空间
permitted only a limited number of sweeps through the state space.
执行有限次数的策略评估步骤
In other words, we limit the number of times that the estimated value of
换句话说 我们将每个状态的估算值更新次数
each state is updated before proceeding to the policy improvement round.
限定为一定的数量 然后再进行策略完善
In this video, you will learn about Value Iteration,
在本视频中 你将学习值迭代
where the policy evaluation step is stopped after a single sweep.
在循环一次后停止策略评估步骤
It is really as simple as that,
真的就这么简单
but it turns out that you can simplify the underlying code,
实际上 你可以简化底层代码
and we will derive the simple form together over the remainder of this video.
我们将在本视频的剩余时间内得出简单形式
So let us write down the pseudo code
我们写出每个评估和完善步骤
corresponding to each of these evaluation and improvement steps.
对应的伪代码
And the first thing to notice is that we can collapse
首先要注意的是
these lines to remove a bit of redundancy.
我们可以整合这几行 避免冗余
In particular, the action value from
尤其是 可以将第一行的动作值
the first line can be plugged in where it appears in the second line.
代入第二行
Now recall that this policy improvements step is
注意 这个策略完善步骤
followed by another policy evaluation step.
后面跟着另一个策略评估步骤
Pi prime is used as the new value of policy pi,
策略 π′ 是策略 π 的新值
which is then put through a single sweep of policy evaluation.
然后用该值完成一次策略评估
Okay, so we can quickly see another bit of redundancy here.
很快发现这里也有冗余
Instead of updating pi prime and then
我们不再更新 π′
immediately using it to set the new value of policy pi,
并立即将它设为策略 π 的新值
what we can do is just directly update the value of policy pi from the value function.
而是直接在值函数中更新策略 π 的值
Next, we'll need to look at these two equations a bit closer.
接着 我们需要更仔细地研究这两个方程
And when we do that, we notice that they're nearly the same.
我们发现它俩几乎一样
In particular, everything that appears after the sum is nearly identical,
具体而言 求和之后的所有元素几乎一样
with the exception of the values here.
但是这里的值除外
It turns out that we can combine
实际上 我们可以整合这两行
these two lines to produce a single line that accomplishes the same effect.
并生成效果一样的一行公式
Towards that, we'll first note that pi of S is the ARG Max
为此 我们首先需要注意
over all actions of some semi-complicated expression,
π(s) 是某个比较复杂的表达式的所有动作的 ARG Max
but we can think of this long thing as a function of the action A.
我们可以将这一大串看做动作 a 的函数
Then, V of S is a sign that same function,
然后 V(s) 使用相同的函数
but evaluated at pi of S. So if pi of S is set to
但是计算的是在 π(s) 的值
the ARG Max and V of S this is set to the function evaluated at that ARG Max,
如果 π(s) 设为 ARG Max 而 V(s) 设为 ARG Max 时计算出的函数值
well, then we could just directly set V of S to the max of
那么我们可以直接将 V(s) 设为该函数的最大值
the function until we can plug this in to our algorithm.
然后将这个代入我们的算法
We begin with an initial guess of the value function.
我们先对值函数进行初始猜测
The algorithm loops over the state space and
算法循环访问状态空间
successively applies the update rule to get a better guess at the value function.
成功地应用更新规则以便更准确地猜测值函数
After each update, we check to see if the value function estimate has converged.
每次更新后 我们都检查值函数逼近结果是否已收敛
And in case it has,
如果已收敛
we stop this part of the algorithm.
则停止算法的这一部分
After convergence, there is one last step to get
收敛后 需要完成最后一步
the policy corresponding to the final value function.
才能获得对应于最终值函数的策略
Once you are ready, follow the instructions in
准备好后 请按照下个部分的说明操作
the next concept to implement this algorithm yourself.
自己实现该算法